Marc Gallagher-Reid Full Stack Developer

CONTACT

- **2** 07846051106
- @ mgrdevuk@gmail.com
- W https://mgallagher56.github.io/

Technologies

HTML 5





ES 6



PHP 7





I'm an enthusiastic full stack developer with a passion for fun, distinctive front end design. Outside of software development, I enjoy custom PC design/building and I'm a keen runner and footballer. I'm always happy to take part in local/company 5-a-side teams or running clubs, as well as other social events. I can regularly be found recruiting colleagues and friends to take part in the nearest pub quiz.



Skills



I am currently studying at Mayden Academy, a 16 week intensive full stack development course. During this time I have become a certified Scrum Master, produced 6 projects as part of an Agile team and also completed a number of personal projects. The most relevant projects are described below and all my projects can be viewed at: http://bit.ly/mgrPortfolio

Projects

Matching Card Pairs Game

JavaScript

Site: http://bit.ly/mgrPairsGame GitHub Repo: http://bit.ly/mgrPairsGameGitHub

Working as part of an Agile team, we created a card game to find and match pairs of images. We took an iterative approach using Scrum to develop the project in stages, working on core functionality before adding nice to have features. We worked using ES6 for Dom manipulation, using a main game object to manage game states and attributes then used event listeners to detect and change cards states.

Recipe Search App

OOP PHP

Site: http://bit.ly/mgrGrub GitHub Repo: http://bit.ly/mgrGrubGitHub

As an Agile team, we created an app to generate recipes from given ingredients using the RecipePuppy API. We developed this using object orientated Php, including using a hydrator design pattern, using curl to make HTTP request and unit testing. As with all our projects, we used Git for version control and GitHub for collaboration and code reviews.

Employment



July 2018 - Present

After noticing a gap in the market, I established a cleaning company, recruited, interviewed, hired and managed cleaning staff specifically for short-term holiday lets. The company currently provides daily cleaning services for 15 properties around Bath.

Marc Gallagher-Reid

Full Stack Developer

CONTACT

- **7** 07846051106
- @ mgrdevuk@gmail.com
- W https://mgallagher56.github.io/

Employment

Bath AirShare Ltd t/a Bath Holiday Houses Holiday Let Property Management ->

September 2017 - August 2019

Director

My responsibilities incorporated all aspects of digital management for the company, including website design/development, platform expansion, and developing automation and efficiency improvements across the business.

After a year of working at the company, I was given a Director role to establish more efficient processes across all aspects of the business. In my 2 years at the company, managed properties increased from 3 to 21 with one additional staff member, managing $\mathfrak{L}50,000$ worth of bookings in 2017 to $\mathfrak{L}400,000$ in 2019.

Walgreens Boots Alliance - Nottingham, UK & Zaragoza, Spain

January 2017
- September 2017

IT Intern

I joined WBA on a 9 month IT Internship across 3 areas of the business. I gained knowledge of Agile and Scrum, along with project management and governance in the Pharmacy Transformation Programme - Columbus, in Nottingham.

From here I progressed to Zaragoza in Spain, working with the Alliance Healthcare team in the quality assurance department.

I spent my final 3 months with the company back in Nottingham, working in Global Brands, in IT Service Management.

Education

Mayden Academy - Bath, UK

August -December 2019

Full-Stack Development Bootcamp

I'm currently attending a full time, 16 week course focusing on Full Stack Development, including 7 week-long agile projects covering HTMI, CSS, JavaScript and Php.

Rathmore Grammar School - Belfast, UK

2004-2011

A - Levels

Sociology - B, Biology - B, Business Studies - B